A man called "Horse" becomes an Indian warrior in the
most electrifying ritual ever seen!
A Man Called Horse is a western, drama film directed by Elliot Silverstein.
In 1825, English peer Lord John Morgan is cast adrift in the American West.
Captured by Sioux Indians, Morgan is at first targeted for quick
extinction, but the tribesmen sense that he is worthy of survival.
He eventually passes the many necessary tests that will
permit him to become a member of the tribe.
John Morgan, played by Richard Harris.
Batise, played by Jean Gascon.
Buffalo Cow Head, played by Judith Anderson.
Running Deer, played by Corinna Tsopei.
Yellow Hand, played by Manu Tupou.
Joe, played by Dub Taylor.
A Man Called Horse is a 1970 Western film directed by Elliot
Silverstein, produced by Sandy Howard, and written by Jack DeWitt.
It is based on a short story of the same name by the Western writer Dorothy M.
Johnson, first published in 1950 in Collier's magazine and
again in 1968 in Johnson's book Indian Country.
The basic story was used in a 1958 episode of the television
series Wagon Train, also titled "A Man Called Horse".
The film stars Richard Harris as the titular character, alongside Judith Anderson,
Jean Gascon, Manu Tupou, Corinna Tsopei, Dub Taylor, and James Gammon.
Partially spoken in Sioux, the film tells the story of an English
aristocrat who is captured by the Sioux people.
The film was a Mexican-American co-production filmed on location in
Arizona and the Mexican states of Durango and Sonora.
It received generally positive critical reviews, and was a financial success, spawning two sequels;
The Return of a Man Called Horse (1976) and Triumphs of a Man Called Horse (1983).
The film explores themes of ambush, ritual, indian
territory, native american, aristocrat.
The tone is emotional.